

# **DE VITERBO, MARTY**

Portfolio: https://deviterbo.vercel.app

**GitHub:** https://github.com/mmdeviterbo

**Email:** mmdeviterbo@up.edu.ph

## **Summary**

A software developer specializing back end and moreover front-end development. Experienced and well- versed in programming languages and/or technologies such as ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJS/NodeJS, Python, Java, C, SQL, and MongoDB. Lead as a project manager and team leader in previous projects, strong background in project management and has best relations with both co-developer and client.

# **Skill Highlights**

- Project management
- Technology Adaptability
- Creative design and animation
- Complex problem solver
- Innovative
- UI/UX Frameworks

## **Experience**

**Developer** | January 2022 to May 2022

ElBids: Online Auction System

- https://elbids.vercel.app/
- Develop (as a solo) an online auction system for UPLB stakeholders
- Utilize the latest technologies: NextJS, Apollo-GraphQL, NodeJS, MaterialUI

#### **Software Engineer Intern** | June 2021 to August 2021

Dashlabs.ai | Simplifying Healthcare

- https://www.dashlabs.ai/
- Full-stack debugging
- Improve the system by joining the Software Quality Assurance (QA) Team using Jest
- Improve and develop front-end interface

#### Project Manager | April 2021 to June 2021

UPLB Institute of Computer Science Online Library System

- https://analytica-library.vercel.app/
- Team up with developers to create elegant interfaces, friendly interactions, and experiences.
- Develop and organize project optimal workflow of the system
- Work and lead with talented developer to manage complex design system
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end as well as efficiency onback-end side program
- Implement quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability of the system

### Front end Team Leader | January 2020 to December 2020

Hotel Management System

- A volunteer work to develop user interface that is particularly suited with low-level of knowledge on using a computer
- Manage to handle the technology or frameworks to have a consistency in the interface
- Prioritize and implement mobile responsiveness application

### Python Developer | August 2018 to December 2018

Checkers (Dama Boardgame)

- Recreate the checkers boardgame using Python
- Optimize the game with faster running time
- Output correct logs during the game

## Membership and Internals Affair Member | 1/2019 to present

Alliance of Computer Science Students

• Increased efficiency and performance by monitoring team member productivity and providing feedback. Organizing and leading major events of the organization.

### **Publication Committee Member** | 1/2019 to present

**UP Munscials Alumni Society** 

 Enhanced publication design initiatives while managing effective marketing campaigns. Created trend boards, investigated recommended strategic adoptions to capitalize on projected changes

## **Education**

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science | University of the Philippines, Los Baños

2018-2022

Magna Cum Laude with eight consecutives in achieving university scholar maintaining GPA of above 1.5

High School Diploma | Muntinlupa Science Highschool

2012 - 2018

Two consecutives in achieving high-honors on K-12 curriculum with average of 97

# **Languages**

#### **Tagalog**

**Primary** 

#### **English**

Secondary